<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://briancherin.github.io">
    <title>Brian&#39;s Garden</title>
    <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://briancherin.github.io" />
    <updated>2025-12-22T17:46:10Z</updated>
    <id>https://briancherin.github.io</id>
        <entry>
            <title>
                This is the beginning
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-19T21:51:57.041Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;h1 id=&quot;this-is-the-beginning&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;This is the beginning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of my digital garden / blog thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A starting point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/what-is-this/&quot;&gt;What Is This&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button id=&quot;random-note-button&quot;&gt;🎲 Go to Random Note&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
let notes = null;

async function loadNotes() {
  if (notes) return notes;
  const res = await fetch(&quot;/searchIndex.json&quot;);
  const data = await res.json();
  notes = data.map(e =&gt; e.url);
  return notes;
}

async function goToRandomNote() {
  const notes = await loadNotes();
  const random = notes[Math.floor(Math.random() * notes.length)];
  if (random == &quot;/&quot;) {
	  await goToRandomNote();
  }
  window.location.href = random;
}

document.getElementById(&quot;random-note-button&quot;)
  .addEventListener(&quot;click&quot;, goToRandomNote);
&lt;/script&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Specific Main App Pursuit I&#39;m Currently Working On
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-09T23:24:30.133Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/specific-main-app-pursuit-i-m-currently-working-on/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#project&quot;&gt;#project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/specific-main-app-pursuit-i-m-currently-working-on/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                brianiscool.tk
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-09T00:02:55.577Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/really-old-projects/brianiscool-tk/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#project&quot;&gt;#project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website was one of the first coding projects I worked on, back in high school. My version of a portfolio but a bit silly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally hosted it using a webhost called 000webhost (I don&#39;t think it exists anymore) and Freenom for a free domain name (probably free because it was for non-traditional domain endings, like &amp;quot;.tk&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;.cw&amp;quot;). Eventually I forgot to keep renewing the domain and probably the hosting broke at some point, but luckily I had the original source files saved locally (or maybe on Github actually) so I turned it into a Github Pages site which is mostly functional to what it was originally like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/brianiscool/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://briancherin.github.io/brianiscool/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scavenger hunt / things to watch out for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Random color generator (not on the homepage!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Farm animal game (weirdly fun but eventually not balanced)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bee Haven game (warning that this is not particularly mobile-friendly but it&#39;ll still work)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try not to fall into the Trap (the curse of 100 alert dialogs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/really-old-projects/brianiscool-tk/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Restaurant AI VR Simulation
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-09T23:28:18.794Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/mini-projects/restaurant-ai-vr-simulation/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#project&quot;&gt;#project&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#miniproject&quot;&gt;#miniproject&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/mini-projects/restaurant-ai-vr-simulation/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Mini Projects
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-09T23:29:44.201Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/mini-projects/mini-projects/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#coding&quot;&gt;#coding&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#project&quot;&gt;#project&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#miniproject&quot;&gt;#miniproject&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;block-language-dataview&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/mini-projects/restaurant-ai-vr-simulation/&quot;&gt;Restaurant AI VR Simulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/please-don-t-spearphish-me-creating-an-obsidian-plugin/&quot;&gt;Please Don&#39;t Spearphish Me (Creating an Obsidian Plugin)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/mini-projects/mini-projects/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Bee Haven
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-10T03:07:38.910Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/game-development/old-projects/bee-haven/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#gamedev&quot;&gt;#gamedev&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#project&quot;&gt;#project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Projects/Software/Game%20Development/Old%20projects/Assets/bee%20haven%20title.png&quot; alt=&quot;bee haven title.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A game I made during a high school summer program I attended in summer of 2018. It&#39;s an infinite scroller. You control a bee&#39;s movement to the left and right as it moves forward toward the horizon, collecting flowers and avoiding birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graphics were very simplistic (I vaguely wanted to make them better in the future but never went back to it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Projects/Software/Game%20Development/Old%20projects/Assets/bee%20haven%20gameplay.png&quot; alt=&quot;bee haven gameplay.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I published it to the Google Play Store (under a pseudonym because I was very resistant to publishing things under my real name back then) but eventually it got taken down because I needed to update things to comply with Google&#39;s new developer rules (possibly could&#39;ve been something as easy as adding a privacy policy to my app, but I just never bothered to expend the energy to do whatever it needed me to do).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But also recently, I&#39;ve been wanting to show people a demo of the game. I recently tried to re-install it on my phone by using an old APK (app installation file for Android) that I downloaded from the Google Play Dev Console, but installation failed because the architecture of the app was too out of date. There is, however, a usable version of the game that can be accessed via &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/really-old-projects/brianiscool-tk/&quot;&gt;brianiscool.tk&lt;/a&gt;, so in theory I can show people from that, but I&#39;d prefer the app experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;task-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_0&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_0&quot;&gt; Run it locally and build it to Android, test it&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_1&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_1&quot;&gt; Try re-publishing it to the Play Store???&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_2&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_2&quot;&gt; Could also think about what improvements I could make (though tbh don&#39;t feel it&#39;s the place for me to invest my energy in anytime soon, especially with projects like &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/specific-main-app-pursuit-i-m-currently-working-on/&quot;&gt;Specific Main App Pursuit I&#39;m Currently Working On&lt;/a&gt; on top of my mind)&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/game-development/old-projects/bee-haven/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Game Dev Inspiration
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-10T03:08:23.494Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/game-development/game-dev-inspiration/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#gamedev&quot;&gt;#gamedev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YtylfQq2JII&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Make Tiny Games.&amp;quot; by Juniper Dev (youtube)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made me feel a brief moment of inspiration to code up small games - clones of existing ones with modifications, or just novel simple ones. Mostly made me think of &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/game-development/old-projects/bee-haven/&quot;&gt;Bee Haven&lt;/a&gt;, which is sort of a subway surfer clone I made during high school. I&#39;ve recently been thinking of repolishing and republishing it to the Play Store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/game-development/game-dev-inspiration/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Personal 3D VR World Building
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-22T03:10:23.858Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/projects/3-d-and-vr/personal-3-d-vr-world-building/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had many ideas related to this topic. I can explain it in more depth in the future, but for right now I&#39;m just going to paste a tiny thought-stream question I asked ChatGPT and then the AI response. Just a little bit of ideating for something I know I want to spend more time on in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I want want 3d environment building to be an art form, a kind of journaling and exploration and expression, an interconnected world of 3d/vr environments, make scenes tying music to memories, bringing paintings to life, creating representations of my favorite scenes from fiction, crafting environments of all the bedrooms of my life, in a way that is extensible and not software-locked as much as possible moving forward into the future, in a way that allows me to access and explore these scenes in an interconnected and stable way, allowing me to do something like having a virtual hallway allowing access into different rooms which show these various scenes, or having a portal room to bring me to the scenes, my own personal 3d world, how should i do it and make it and organize it and store it
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!WARNING]- Chat GPT Response&lt;br /&gt;
You’re essentially building a long-lived personal &lt;strong&gt;spatial archive&lt;/strong&gt; rather than a single VR project: an interconnected set of 3D environments that function as journaling, memory, and artistic expression. The core goal is continuity over time—being able to add scenes indefinitely, explore them through symbolic navigation like hallways or portals, and return to them years later without being trapped in a dead piece of software. Treat the world as a personal mythos or memory palace, where meaning matters as much as visual fidelity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this sustainable, separate the work into layers. First is the &lt;strong&gt;concept layer&lt;/strong&gt;: short written “scene cards” that capture what each environment represents, the memory or emotion behind it, associated music, and how it connects to other scenes. This lives in plain text or Markdown and is your true journal. Second is the &lt;strong&gt;asset layer&lt;/strong&gt;, stored in open, portable formats (glTF/GLB for models, PNG/JPG for textures, WAV/FLAC for audio). Each scene gets its own folder, like an album, so the assets can outlive any engine or tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;scene-building layer&lt;/strong&gt; uses replaceable software. Tools like Blender are ideal for creation, but their project files are working files, not the archive itself. Always export clean, engine-agnostic versions of scenes. For exploration, use a runtime engine (ideally something open like Godot) that loads scenes dynamically from a hub or portal space. This keeps scenes loosely coupled and makes it possible to change engines later without rebuilding everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music and sound should be treated as first-class elements of each scene, stored separately and documented alongside the visuals. When bringing paintings or fiction into 3D, focus on translating emotional and symbolic qualities rather than literal realism—lighting, spatial rhythm, and abstraction often convey memory better than accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, protect the work over time. Use version control for text and metadata, archive assets carefully, and periodically “freeze” scenes by exporting models, videos, and written reflections. Start small—one room, one memory, one piece of music—and let the world grow organically. The result is not just a VR environment, but a durable, explorable record of your inner life that can evolve with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/projects/3-d-and-vr/personal-3-d-vr-world-building/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Random Snippets
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-16T16:27:22.607Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/misc/random-snippets/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;Blog that talks about associations between their travel memories and specific music/albums/artists. I could see myself doing something similar with music associations. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mfranchi.net/posts/springs-best-25/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://mfranchi.net/posts/springs-best-25/&lt;/a&gt; (12/14/2025)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This is why I’m not afraid to take my own case to trial because even if I fail or even if I fight and lose, —at least I fought for you.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://thewrittenaddiction.com/2025/12/15/all-for-more-or-less-35/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://thewrittenaddiction.com/2025/12/15/all-for-more-or-less-35/&lt;/a&gt; -- Seems like a poetry-based blog. Slogan of the site is &amp;quot;Where I go to leave pieces of me&amp;quot;. I like that. (12/16/2025)&lt;/p&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/misc/random-snippets/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                What Is This
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-16T16:08:28.520Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/what-is-this/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#digitalgarden&quot;&gt;#digitalgarden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my &amp;quot;digital garden&amp;quot;. It&#39;s sort of a blog, sort of a personal wiki. It&#39;s a place for me to comment on media I&#39;ve consumed, share about my interests and personal projects, and document my viewpoints or anything else I want to share with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-inspired-this&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;What inspired this?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had the idea of writing in a blog format for a while -- see &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/my-past-self-telling-me-to-start-a-blog/&quot;&gt;My Past Self Telling Me To Start a Blog&lt;/a&gt;. Idea blossomed into reality after I watched a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6fj-OJ6RcNQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which introduced the idea of a digital garden. I then read more about the concept in &lt;a href=&quot;https://maggieappleton.com/garden-history&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What directly appealed to me about the concept of a &amp;quot;digital garden&amp;quot; is that it&#39;s not a blog with an underlying purpose like promoting a product or gaining ad revenue. Instead, it&#39;s just a way for someone to express themselves to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I&#39;ve read handfuls of personal blogs before, I never connected the dots that it&#39;s something that just anyone could do. It seemed like you have to have a really strong and cohesive message or goal to put out there if you&#39;re going to be one of those people who starts a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&#39;s a garden, not a farm. You plant some seeds and tend to the plants as they grow. Anyone can do it. Things don&#39;t have to be super polished. You can write a full-blown article about a topic you&#39;re interested in, or just a couple bullet points about an idea you recently had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-makes-it-a-digital-garden-and-not-a-blog&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;What makes it a digital garden and not a blog?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&#39;s both?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a digital garden has an emphasis on a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts don&#39;t have to be perfectly polished - they can be incomplete or in-progress at any given moment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts aren&#39;t viewed as untouchable pieces of work - they can be changed and updated over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts aren&#39;t organized chronologically like in a typical blog. The preferred method of navigation is through categories or tags, or through backlinks from posts to posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://maggieappleton.com/garden-history&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; goes into more detail about some of these points, and is worth a read if you&#39;re interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-do-i-hope-for-a-reader-to-get-out-of-this-site&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;What do I hope for a reader to get out of this site?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be entertained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover new resources, ideas, interests, or concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand me better and have a glimpse into how my mind works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-do-i-hope-for-myself-to-get-out-of-this-site&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;What do I hope for myself to get out of this site?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/reasons-to-write-here/&quot;&gt;Reasons to Write (Here)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-i-make-this-site&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;How did I make this site?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a text editor called Obsidian, which makes it easy to have a hierarchy of many interconnected notes, and publish to Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also see &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/meta/obsidian-setup/&quot;&gt;Obsidian Setup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-in-the-world-do-i-think-is-going-to-read-this&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Who in the world do I think is going to read this?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps friends or family I share it with. But also over time, random people from the World Wide Web. At some point, I&#39;d like to add it to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kagi.com/small-web&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;Kagi Small Web&lt;/a&gt; feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if my audience is extremely tiny, I still feel motivated to write here. It&#39;s a long-term project representing myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot; /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Brainrot Apocalypse (a DIY survival guide)&amp;quot; by Struthless. Relevant part at about 26:45 but the whole video is worth watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/what-is-this/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Reasons to Write (Here)
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-12T02:14:26.939Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/reasons-to-write-here/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing any writing makes me a better writer by developing the skill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expressing my ideas and sharing them with people, which can lead to connection (with people), collaboration, insight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing things out provides a means of developing ideas, possibly leading towards insights and connections (between ideas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/reasons-to-write-here/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Please Don&#39;t Spearphish Me (Creating an Obsidian Plugin)
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-12T01:04:41.664Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/please-don-t-spearphish-me-creating-an-obsidian-plugin/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#digitalgarden&quot;&gt;#digitalgarden&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#obsidian&quot;&gt;#obsidian&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#cybersecurity&quot;&gt;#cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#privacy&quot;&gt;#privacy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#project&quot;&gt;#project&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#coding&quot;&gt;#coding&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#miniproject&quot;&gt;#miniproject&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anytime I make a new public appearance (like making a new social media account, or this blog) I ask myself: am I revealing too much about myself to the Internet? I have some background in cybersecurity (meaning: a handful of classes at university), so I have some mental framework that lets me contemplate the consequences of having information about myself online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a little voice in my head saying not to publish an article with this title (&amp;quot;please don&#39;t spearphish me&amp;quot;) because it might act as reverse psychology and give someone the idea to do it just because I mentioned it. Please don&#39;t be that person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my point here is that I&#39;m building some level of a safeguard for myself. A tool that might help me catch myself before revealing too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this a perfect solution? No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I overthinking this? Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But just like my footnote in my &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/podcasts/1-second-everyday-indie-hackers-podcast/&quot;&gt;1 Second Everyday - Indie Hackers Podcast&lt;/a&gt; post (&amp;quot;It&#39;s scary sometimes how easy it might be to ruin your own life&amp;quot;), I feel that exposing some little piece of information about yourself in public could cause some mess for you. At best? Someone being creepy and sending you weird messages. At worst? Someone identifying a routine that you have and stalking you in real life. Or just hacking you via a spearphishing email that contains a link or download you mindlessly click.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&#39;s my little solution for this? An Obsidian plugin that will audit the current note I&#39;ve written and tell me if I&#39;m revealing too much information in the post. (Obsidian is the text editor I use to write these blog posts, and I use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oleeskild/Obsidian-Digital-Garden&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;Obsidian Digital Garden plugin&lt;/a&gt; for help building+publishing to this site.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the workflow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the plugin (see instructions on the Github repo, linked below) and set your OpenAI API key in the plugin settings. You can also modify the system prompt that tells the AI how to interpret your note and what the output should look like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You write a note in Obsidian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the command palette (ctrl/cmd + P) and run &amp;quot;Privacy Audit&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The request will be processed by the OpenAI API and the result will be opened in a side panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-details&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;More details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used ChatGPT to help me code this up. It didn&#39;t take long to set it up locally and test it out in Obsidian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin uses the OpenAI API to ask GPT to review the note and make any suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve published the code to my Github &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/briancherin/obsidian-ai-privacy-audit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and I&#39;ve made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/obsidianmd/obsidian-releases/pull/8887&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;Pull Request&lt;/a&gt; on the Obsidian repo to get this added to the community plugin list so that anyone can access it. A fun little open-source contribution that I hope someone might find helpful! I&#39;m pretty new to the Obsidian and Digital Gardening scene, so I hope the universe will forgive me if something like this already exists (I swear, I don&#39;t mean to flood the plugin list with slop).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;examples&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The command:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Meta/On%20Blogging/Assets/Images/dontspearpishme-command-palette.png&quot; alt=&quot;dontspearpishme-command-palette.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin catches my reveal of a routine:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Meta/On%20Blogging/Assets/Images/dontspearphishme-example1.png&quot; alt=&quot;dontspearphishme-example1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin catches my reveal of corporate information:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Meta/On%20Blogging/Assets/Images/dontspearphishme-example2.png&quot; alt=&quot;dontspearphishme-example2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No issues with this one! It gives some extraneous suggestions about my clearly engaging content:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Meta/On%20Blogging/Assets/Images/dontspearphishme-example3.png&quot; alt=&quot;dontspearphishme-example3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;areas-for-improvement&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Areas for improvement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a command to run an audit for every file in the vault individually and get a summary of suggested fixes for each&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a command to do a comprehensive audit across the whole vault, in case little bits of information in each file add up to a bigger picture (violating your privacy) which wouldn&#39;t be revealed within just one file. (This may be complicated since all the files won&#39;t fit in one GPT context window. There&#39;d have to be some processing.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a similar audit to the Github pipeline that actually gets triggered when I publish a note, so I don&#39;t have to remember to manually run the audit within Obsidian. If there is a critical warning, maybe fail the job, or maybe just alert me somehow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;concluding-words&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Concluding words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a feeling I might think of other AI-related Obsidian plugins in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-retrospect-from-two-days-later&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;A retrospect from two days later&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2025-12-10) Retrospectively, what I mostly actually developed here was a GPT wrapper for a single-prompt analysis of the current note. The only thing making it a &amp;quot;security audit&amp;quot; plugin is the system prompt, which is modifiable in the plugin settings. So, anyone could actually change the system prompt for themselves and use it for something different. (This is a good/cool thing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should instead have branded it as a generic GPT overlay. But I do also value the privacy focus because I feel like it&#39;s good to get people to think about it and give them a ready-made tool to do the privacy check up. So maybe I should make a separate plugin that has more emphasis on being a free-form AI tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, without researching this at all, I&#39;d guess that something like that already exists. GPT has been a thing for a while, and I&#39;m sure that someone made a plugin to integrate a full chat into Obsidian. Fine, I&#39;ll check. Found this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/13cuq8w/best_plugin_for_chat_gpt_for_obsidian/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;reddit post&lt;/a&gt; with some suggested plugins for this. I&#39;m not discounting my own plugin, but maybe I don&#39;t need to expand it like I&#39;m saying. At the same time, what I&#39;m really suggesting here is a way for a user to set up any amount of custom commands which will execute one GPT system prompt on the active note. I could see this being a novel plugin idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025-12-11&lt;br /&gt;
Also, I realize that there is some irony/concern with passing the potentially sensitive note content to AI to scan for said potentially sensitive content. The tradeoff is, do I want to reveal my personal details to the Internet, or reveal them to an AI (read: the corporation running the AI)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, my PR for the Obsidian plugin has kind of stalled, and I&#39;m not feeling much motivation to push hard on it. Might be something I just let float around until I feel more strongly about it. It&#39;s a really teeny tiny mini project, not a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/please-don-t-spearphish-me-creating-an-obsidian-plugin/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                My Past Self Telling Me To Start a Blog
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-10T19:06:37.759Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/my-past-self-telling-me-to-start-a-blog/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;Digging in the archives of my Google Keep notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From May 5, 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]&lt;br /&gt;
Start a blog, because cool people have blogs. But don&#39;t do it for money or fame. Do it to write about things you like writing about, and if anyone reads it, that will be reward in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unicycling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complaints about society or myself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(My past self was a little bit performative about the concept of &amp;quot;being cool&amp;quot;, but it was mostly in a silly joking way and more about inspiring myself to do interesting things with my time.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From June 8, 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]&lt;br /&gt;
When there&#39;s an interesting quote or passage or idea in a book you&#39;re reading, write about it (use those skills from all your English classes over the years) and maybe make a blog post about it! Who knows, maybe someone will be interested in your thoughts. But do pure thoughts. Okay, not &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#thoughtstream&quot;&gt;#thoughtstream&lt;/a&gt; thoughts, as this is approaching, (well this style would be fine for a blogpost, if not excellent for displaying my personality) but don&#39;t flourish the writing - make it true to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m guessing the above note was inspired by this line from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/84699.Never_Eat_Alone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;Never Eat Alone&lt;/a&gt; that I highlighted also on June 8, 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!Warning] Quote&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Acting on an idea—whether it’s as small as writing a blog, or as big as creating a business—sends a shock wave out into the world that flows back even stronger, as others gain interest in your ideas and wish to add their own and new community all gathered around you, energized by your shared interest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From June 3, 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Things I could write about on a blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lt;redacted&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lt;redacted&amp;gt; (eventually)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;juggling, unicycling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China/Japan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The physics of microwave doors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hour of code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product reviews! Once your blog starts growing, you can start places for free stuff (eg filament)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electronics robot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(No, I&#39;m not sure why physics of microwave doors is on this list.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From June 6, 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Blog name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Life flow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From January 2, 2021:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Argument for having a blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;quot;Reach out to like-minded people.... Having a public blog... with small amount of content expressing your thoughts and ideas is helpful [for meeting people]&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2020/11/23/missing-foundation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2020/11/23/missing-foundation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From December 11, 2024:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]&lt;br /&gt;
Blog name: Brian, Master of None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above note expanded on October 23, 2025:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]&lt;br /&gt;
Brian&#39;s Corner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, on December 6, 2025, the day before I started this Digital Garden and wrote &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/podcasts/1-second-everyday-indie-hackers-podcast/&quot;&gt;my first post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]&lt;br /&gt;
Digital Garden -- related to my ideas for blog / personal website / answer to my wondering about use of social media to share projects and interests and [engage?] and such&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://maggieappleton.com/garden-history&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://maggieappleton.com/garden-history&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Found from this good video which has other great ideas too &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/6fj-OJ6RcNQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/6fj-OJ6RcNQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/my-past-self-telling-me-to-start-a-blog/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Blogging Inspiration
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-10T18:58:25.087Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/blogging-inspiration/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://strikingloo.github.io/wiki/essays&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://strikingloo.github.io/wiki/essays&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/meta/on-blogging/blogging-inspiration/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Obsidian Setup
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-13T17:10:40.794Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/meta/obsidian-setup/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#obsidian&quot;&gt;#obsidian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the setup for this blog is handled by the  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oleeskild/Obsidian-Digital-Garden&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;Obsidian Digital Garden plugin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current theme from the Obsidian Digital Garden theme library is &amp;quot;Blue Topaz&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;webpage-footer&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Webpage footer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dg-docs.ole.dev/advanced/adding-custom-components&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;custom components&lt;/a&gt; guide for the DG plugin, I added the link to my feedback form using a footer component which I manually added in &lt;code&gt;src/site/_includes/components/user/notes/footer/feedback-form.njk&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/briancherin/briancherin.github.io/blob/main/src/site/_includes/components/user/notes/footer/feedback-form.njk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;github link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;feed-xml-fix&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Feed.xml fix&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Obsidian Digital Garden plugin automatically generates an RSS feed at the /feed.xml route at the root of the site. But when I navigated there, I saw this error:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;error on line 48 at column 17: Opening and ending tag mismatch: link line 47 and entry&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oleeskild/obsidian-digital-garden/issues/493&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://github.com/oleeskild/obsidian-digital-garden/issues/493&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I found this &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;Github issue&lt;/a&gt; that helped resolve this. The solution was to manually go into the site&#39;s Github repo and edit &lt;code&gt;src/site/feed.njk&lt;/code&gt; so that all of the &amp;lt;link&amp;gt; tags have a closing tag with five backslashes instead of four (yes this is a weird error/workaround).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;setting-custom-domain-name&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Setting custom domain name&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added &lt;a href=&quot;http://garden.briancher.in/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;garden.briancher.in&lt;/a&gt; as my domain in Github Pages settings, but it got cleared any time I published a note from Obsidian. Thankfully I quickly found a note in the repo&#39;s readme which said I needed to add the domain also to .github/workflows/build.yml.&lt;/p&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/meta/obsidian-setup/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Garden Improvements
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-17T20:15:22.661Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/meta/garden-improvements/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#digitalgarden&quot;&gt;#digitalgarden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;task-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_0&quot; checked=&quot;true&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_0&quot;&gt; (Done 12/13/2025) Set my own favicon instead of the default&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_1&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_1&quot;&gt; add a commenting system&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;task-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_2&quot; checked=&quot;true&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_2&quot;&gt; (Done, 12/8/2025) Or at least an (optionally-anonymous) feedback/contact form in the mean time&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_3&quot; checked=&quot;true&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_3&quot;&gt; make it so the date published and date last updated appears on pages&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_4&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_4&quot;&gt; make a list of my hobbies/interests (and then eventually link pages/folders from them)&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_5&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_5&quot;&gt; be able to see page view count (analytics) (possibly some good guidance &lt;a href=&quot;https://tjpalanca.com/2023/05/20/nerfing-google-analytics.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_6&quot; checked=&quot;true&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_6&quot;&gt; (Done, 12/8/2025) Fix /feed.xml so it can generate RSS feed. There&#39;s an issue with the html snippet on the homepage for the &#39;random note&#39; button&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_7&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_7&quot;&gt; Post this site to Kagi Small Web&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_8&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_8&quot;&gt; Make a visualization to see frequency of posts over time&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_9&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_9&quot;&gt; May want to eventually setup Obsidian to host images/other_assets on S3 instead of on Github. The Digital Garden plugin mentioned that the site may slow down if the assets pile up since you can&#39;t store that much on Github. I found this Obsidian &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/biubiubiu35/image-paste-to-cloud&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;plugin&lt;/a&gt; which might be the solution for an auto-S3 upload of images.&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cbx_10&quot; disabled=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cbx_10&quot;&gt; Add on-hover preview to footnotes so you can preview content without jumping to bottom of page&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/meta/garden-improvements/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Hank Green Tells Me To Fall Downhill
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-10T03:16:44.113Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/videos/hank-green-tells-me-to-fall-downhill/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;Video title: &amp;quot;Don&#39;t Follow Your Dreams, Follow Your Tools&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
Channel: Hank Green&lt;br /&gt;
Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f_Rqf-vxBM8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f_Rqf-vxBM8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;relevant-part-of-the-video&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Relevant part of the video:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;When they&#39;re like, &#39;how do you decide what to do?&#39; -- &#39;I fall downhill,&#39; is what I say. I am not swimming upstream, very rarely. I might be swimming upstream in terms of the broader culture, but in terms of my skillset and my toolkit and my values, I am doing the easy thing at any given moment. Because I only have so much energy. And there are times when I&#39;m doing the hard thing. But it&#39;s only ever because I am obliged too, like I have to become of some obligation that I have that I would feel like a true monster to ignore.... The idea isn&#39;t a good idea if it&#39;s gonna require a tremendous amount of discipline from me. Because I know that I don&#39;t have that discipline.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-thoughts&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;My thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kinda agree/vibe with this and kind of don&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of &amp;quot;falling downhill&amp;quot; feels extremely relevant to me. I have a lot of interests and hobbies and pursuits, and I love the feeling when working on one of them is an easy thing to do, not requiring much effort because I am really into it and can easily reach a flow state. I&#39;ve felt this way recently with writing (like, blog writing, i.e. Here) and piano (either practicing easy sheet music, or doing simple improvisation). Blogging/writing Here feels quite productive in the scheme of my pursuits, and I&#39;m kind of surprising myself at how easy it feels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I have pursuits that I feel are high importance to me that aren&#39;t as easy and that do require more discipline. However I disagree with Mister Green here because I view myself as obligated to pursue these areas, even if I wouldn&#39;t go as far as saying I&#39;d feel like a &amp;quot;monster&amp;quot; to ignore them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, I do feel some resonance with the &amp;quot;monster&amp;quot; thing. My &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/specific-main-app-pursuit-i-m-currently-working-on/&quot;&gt;Specific Main App Pursuit I&#39;m Currently Working On&lt;/a&gt; is not the easiest thing for me to work on&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but I tell myself it&#39;s really important for me to work on because I feel like it can have a high impact on myself and potentially others if I (hopefully) publish it some day. I would kind of feel terrible (/monster) about myself, to myself, if I didn&#39;t give this a fair shot. However, it does feel uphill at times because of the energy required to work on it. But I do have the toolkit. So maybe it&#39;s just a circumstantial thing that makes this a hard project for me (where the circumstances are, code-fatigue from dayjob, and not making the right time/space/energy for this pursuit, and (perhaps often rightfully) spending energy on other aspects of life).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still, I have other areas of pursuit that aren&#39;t &amp;quot;easy&amp;quot; to me but that I would love to get around to working on. Maybe this wording reveals something though -- &amp;quot;get around to&amp;quot;. Not necessarily working on them &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;, instantaneously. Mister Green implies that at any given moment, he falls downhill. But perhaps something that is uphill right now could later be downhill in the future. So, I wait for the right time to work on this other pursuit, because in the future it may become easier. On the one hand, this could be a rationalization that gives way to procrastination (which is why the &amp;quot;monster&amp;quot; thing is important -- there are exceptions where I can enforce that discipline). But on the other hand, this mindset respects my energy and removes possibly unnecessary strain in life (and in hobbies that are usually supposed to be for fun and/or relaxation and etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, though, I&#39;m a strong believer in &amp;quot;embrace discomfort&amp;quot;. Always doing the easiest thing doesn&#39;t feel like it aligns with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple other thoughts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel there&#39;s some relation to: &amp;quot;Do [x] if it aligns with your values&amp;quot; ===&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Do the easiest thing, unless doing the harder thing aligns with your values&amp;quot;. In choosing what to do with my time, I can do the easiest thing, but if there is a harder thing that is in alignment with my values / where I want to go in terms of fulfillment and self-actualization, then I should push myself to do that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I say &amp;quot;easiest thing&amp;quot;, well, the truly easiest thing for me is usually watching tv or a movie or videos. What I&#39;m really talking about here is Pursuits/hobbies. Taken literally, those are not zero energy. But if I&#39;m in the headspace for working on a Pursuit, then there are some that are easier/lower-effort than others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a lot of hobbies/interests/pursuits, so I feel lucky in that even if at any given moment, certain of those pursuits feel easier or harder than others, I can focus on those easiest ones, and trust that in the future, the other ones may be the easier/downhill-facing ones. Trusting that I will get to them eventually. I sometimes also view this idea of getting back to something in the future as an &amp;quot;envelope&amp;quot; that my past self has sealed an idea/motivation in, to be opened by my future self at some point. This also resonates with Barbara Sher&#39;s concept of &amp;quot;Cyclic scanners&amp;quot; which for a while I&#39;ve identified as being closely aligned to my pattern of cycling through interests -- whatever is in cycle right now may be what feels the &amp;quot;easiest&amp;quot; at the moment, and, per Sher&#39;s theory, once I&#39;ve satisfied myself in that area in the short term, something else may catch my attention and become the &amp;quot;easier&amp;quot; thing (but also maybe it&#39;s the harder thing that catches my interest and I decide to devote the discipline to focus on it for that period of time).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot; /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;(though, that&#39;s partly because my coding energy gets sucked up by my day job -- counterargument to this is that I sometimes have other small coding ideas that are super fun and super easy, like my &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/mini-projects/restaurant-ai-vr-simulation/&quot;&gt;Restaurant AI VR Simulation&lt;/a&gt; mini-project (though, I worked on this during a holiday from work)) &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/videos/hank-green-tells-me-to-fall-downhill/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                All nearness pauses while a star can grow (E.E. Cummings)
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-16T04:21:22.056Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/poetry/all-nearness-pauses-while-a-star-can-grow-e-e-cummings/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Media%20I%20Have%20Consumed/Poetry/Assets/all%20nearness%20pauses.png&quot; alt=&quot;all nearness pauses.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I selected and analyzed this poem for my high school English class. It&#39;s probably one of my favorite poems ever, if only because I spent some time puzzling over it, but also I love the imagery and the mysteries that it still contains for me (seriously, still don&#39;t understand &amp;quot;not where not here but neither&#39;s blue most both). Also because I memorized it (just for fun - I wasn&#39;t required to memorize it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to test myself sometimes to see if I still have it memorized -- usually I don&#39;t, except for snippets. It&#39;s kind of fun to piece it back together after all these years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of arbitrary, but thinking about the poem evokes my childhood bedroom in my mind, probably because I had written out the poem on the whiteboard in my room while I was memorizing and analyzing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the lines have really stuck with me. &amp;quot;more he gives than takes&amp;quot; gives me chills -- thinking about what we gain with time rather than what we lose. Also get chills from the last few lines. Something plays in my mind when I read those last lines (well really throughout the whole poem), an image of a sunset, an image of many doors or worlds floating in midair (this must be a remnant of &amp;quot;if a world ends... worlds begin to begin&amp;quot; being the equivalent of &amp;quot;one door closes, another one opens&amp;quot;), and when I read the &amp;quot;(see?)&amp;quot; I literally gasp, a small, sharp intake of breath, or I visualize someone gasping as they see the evidence of what is being told to them, knowing it&#39;s true, seeing something new coming over the horizon.&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m literally going to paste my analysis from that English class below. I do not claim to be 100% on the same page with what my past self wrote here. (some of it honestly seems like a bit of a stretch... But I can&#39;t blame my past self. It&#39;s a complicated and confusing poem!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I feel weird adding this caveat, but my high school era was before AI-generated content, so yes this is analysis is 100% written by me (though, I think I remember getting help for a few things from the web, in particular the word swap thing (&amp;quot;the and peaceful hills&amp;quot;). I think everything else was just from my own contemplation.))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-english-class-analysis&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;My English class analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“all nearness pauses,while a star can grow”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“A star can grow” represents sunset, when the sun (a “star”) appears to “grow” as it approaches the horizon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“All nearness pauses” — the beauty and importance of the setting sun makes anyone watching it “pause” for a moment, staying still and remaining silent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The comma in “pauses,while” emphasizes this pause, even though the comma is grammatically unnecessary. E. E. Cummings frequently uses punctuation to convey deeper meaning in this way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“all distance breathes a final dream of bells;”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As the sun sets, the sounds and events of the day are beginning to die down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The start of the night begins with an exhale of &lt;em&gt;breath&lt;/em&gt;, and the events of the day fade from immediate memory like a “dream”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“perfectly outlined against afterglow”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Afterglow”: light remaining in the sky after the sun has set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also “afterglow”: good feelings remaining after a pleasurable or successful experience
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The setting of the sun could signify the ending of a pleasurable event, or even one’s life. The “outline against afterglow” is the pleasant but fading memory of what is lost to the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“are all amazing the and peaceful hills”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cummings purposely rearranges the standard order of the words in the phrase “are all the amazing and peaceful hills”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He does so to momentarily disorient the audience, emulating the loss of coherent words one experiences when observing a setting sun.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This feature is seen in several other of Cummings’ poems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“(not where not here but neither’s blue most both)”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This perhaps is in response to the question of “Where is the sun setting?”. In response, the narrator responds that &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; is not an appropriate question to ask, and that the sunset also did not occur &lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;. This emphasizes that the sunrise occurs everywhere at once (for one hemisphere), not in just one particular place. Anywhere the sunset has just occurred, the sky will no longer be &lt;em&gt;blue&lt;/em&gt;, because it is now night. However, the sky is only &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt;ly devoid of blueness, because of the “afterglow” leaving behind some color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figuratively, this could be answering the question, “Where did the events of my life occur?”. The answer is that they did not occur in any one place, but rather the impact of the events is so broad in history that their impact can be seen everywhere. Just as the sky is no longer blue after a sunset, the world is not the same as it was after these life events occurred, and the feeling or memory of those events is almost completely gone from one’s mind. However, some residual feelings of the events remain, so they are not yet completely lost.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“and history immeasurably is / wealthier by a single sweet day’s death”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sunset represents another day passing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every day that passes, the events and experiences of that day are added permanently to history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“as not imagined secrecies comprise / goldenly huge whole the uploating moon”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When day ends, the moon remains in the sky to shine over the night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The moon is a symbol of the day’s end and the transition of the next day, made up (“comprised”) of all the things that have not yet come to pass (“not imagined”). These future “secrecies” lie in wait for the coming day to see them to fruition, and meanwhile the moon holds on to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Time’s a strange fellow;/more he gives than takes/(and he takes all)”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personifies the concept of time — the narrator reflects on Time as a peculiar creature who acts in an usually generous way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does time give and take?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time takes youth, vitality, and life, and gives in return experience and wisdom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time takes days of the past, and gives to the future the histories that they contained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“More he gives than takes” —
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The experience and wisdom gained over time are more valuable than the lost youth — losing youth is worth it for what is gained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“More he gives than takes/(and he takes all)” — paradox: implies that Time gives more than “all”. Stresses the great extent to which Time gives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Nor any marvel finds/quite disappearance but some keener makes/losing,gaining”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Marvel”: a wonderful or astonishing person or thing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To this type of person, the days/time/youth that are lost do not “quite” feel like they have disappeared. Instead, they are able to turn losses into gains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking back at the lost days of one’s life should be fulfilling, even if those things can never again be experienced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The narrator implies that the audience should also view their losses in this way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“—love! if a world ends/more than all worlds begin to(see?)begin
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[if a world ends, more than all, worlds begin to begin]
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A closing door means that more doors begin to open, and new opportunities may arise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The day ending means that more days with new opportunities/experiences will follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could also signify the end of one’s life, and the entrance to the afterlife. “See?” may be the narrator gesturing to the audience as they die and enter the afterlife.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The object in question is a “world” — this magnifies the sensation of loss and gain, on the planetary level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall meaning of the poem
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presents an optimistic view of loss, whether it be the loss of a good experience, or the loss of one’s life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is lost is also a gain whether in memory or experience, and the fact of loss means that new things (such as the afterlife) can be experienced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot; /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;also kind of evokes Eliza&#39;s gasp at the end of Hamilton. (I wonder if that Hamilton association is remnant of my interest in it during high school and so it became imbued with this poem, or if it&#39;s just because of the connection to the gasp that I&#39;m thinking about now.) &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/poetry/all-nearness-pauses-while-a-star-can-grow-e-e-cummings/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Daniel Vassallo - Indie Hackers Podcast
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-12T04:10:34.477Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/podcasts/daniel-vassallo-indie-hackers-podcast/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#podcast&quot;&gt;#podcast&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#entrepreneurship&quot;&gt;#entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Episode &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#177&quot;&gt;#177&lt;/a&gt; of the Indie Hackers Podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiehackers.com/podcast/177-daniel-vassallo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Mastering the Lifestyle-First Approach to Indie Hacking with Daniel Vassallo&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; - published October 20, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a good listen. After listening to &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/podcasts/1-second-everyday-indie-hackers-podcast/&quot;&gt;1 Second Everyday - Indie Hackers Podcast&lt;/a&gt; and much enjoying it, I wanted to give another episode a try. I actually asked Chat GPT for the best episodes of the podcast, liked the title of the first one it told me, and listened to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The person being interviewed was Daniel Vassallo, who had been working at Amazon for 6 years, I think as an engineer, earning a high salary ($500k+), and then quit his job to pursue his own things. The podcast was recorded about a year and a half after he quit. A theme was that he pursued several different areas, including developing a SAAS business, a couple other software products, and bringing him the most income were actually some e-books and video courses that he published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has an interesting success story with the ebook/courses because he created them in a small amount of time (weeks or a couple months) and made a lot of money off them -- over $100,000. The software pursuits were more slowly growing, with the SAAS pursuit being the strongest &amp;quot;bet&amp;quot;, but not something he was actively putting more effort into at the moment. (I wonder if this product has grown in the last five years.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;books-course-publishing&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Books/course publishing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m more interested generally in the creation of profitable software products, but it was kind of interesting to hear about the book/course pursuits, too. It makes me wonder what skills I have that I might be able to turn into technical writing or course material. At the same time, I wonder, even if I did have ideas for those things, is my time better off spent on making cool/profitable apps, which interests me more and feels more attuned to my skillset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel a bit silly talking about myself in that way, though, because I generally view myself as having a broad range of skillsets and having many different interests, which includes writing. But I don&#39;t normally think about writing in terms of creating something directly with the intention of making money off it. Writing something technical, like a guide on how to get better at some skill, feels more boring to me than writing fiction, or writing a guide on how to do something but having it free on the Internet. On that last point, though -- it&#39;s cool to have free skillsharing on the Internet, but at some point, it could make sense to develop whatever &amp;quot;guide&amp;quot; it is with more depth and have the &amp;quot;premium&amp;quot; version be the profit-driven book or course. There can be a balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent example of this is the book &amp;quot;Hypnosis Without Trance&amp;quot; by James Tripp. Well, it already is a book in the first place, which in itself is in theory a profit-generating item, but there are a couple (not too many) lines in the book alluding to an online course/program for those interested in going more in depth. I didn&#39;t mind this promotion (/ the existence of the course) because I got a sense that the author was putting the core information into the book, so I wasn&#39;t missing anything, but I could imagine that someone might want to go further, or have hands-on instruction and feedback, thus making the course also valuable to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts/highlights I noted about specific parts of the podcast discussion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can work on a project and publish it, and let it sit for a while, without actively working on it, and come back to it in the future.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This made me think of my work on &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/specific-main-app-pursuit-i-m-currently-working-on/&quot;&gt;Specific Main App Pursuit I&#39;m Currently Working On&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes I view it as: if I have even a little bit of success on it, it&#39;ll be The Thing that I am always working on. But by this advice, I don&#39;t necessarily have to adhere to that. I can get a core form of my app out, and just let people use it and see how it goes. Then I can pick it back up at some point and make improvements to it, or go harder on marketing it more. (But also probably smart to take initial traction and develop from there right away. But still, there can be a breaking point at some point.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The host made a brief comment about the strategy of asking yourself what your future life/lifestyle looks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A perk of having your own business / not having a corporate job is that you get to decide what you want to do every day. Which pursuit to focus on. Reminded me of the &amp;quot;fall downhill&amp;quot; advice from &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/videos/hank-green-tells-me-to-fall-downhill/&quot;&gt;Hank Green Tells Me To Fall Downhill&lt;/a&gt; -- rather than someone telling you to do one specific thing and you having to follow it (or risk job security), you can make the decision on what to work on, and that might be the &amp;quot;easier&amp;quot; thing or the path of least resistance -- the thing you most want or feel like doing in the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on multiple things at once can help smooth out the risk of putting all your eggs in one basket. It might feel scary to work on one thing for six months and then there&#39;s a moment of seeing if you&#39;ll be rewarded for it, or if it doesn&#39;t pay off. Instead, if you work on a couple different things at once, there&#39;s less pressure on any one thing. It&#39;s a way of diversifying.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like this advice because it&#39;s in tune with how I operate. I generally already have different pursuits going on. At different scales too -- different coding projects (or ideas) as well as non-coding projects also (though usually not with a business focus).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&#39;s a tradeoff here of losing focus on any one thing. It really depends on the person&#39;s working style. I think I accel at working on different things at once, and I feel the nervousness that Mr. Vassallo described, of wondering if the One Thing you&#39;re focusing on will work out. I don&#39;t really ever take that risk, though. Doing so is just not how I operate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve tried sometimes to focus all my attention on one thing, and, at least for a recent time I did this, I would get stuck or lose motivation on the One Thing, procrastinate it and not make much progress, but still tell myself that this is the Only Thing I am allowing myself to work on, and nothing else, and so I don&#39;t make progress on anything. If instead I had allowed myself to switch between things more, I may have reduced the strain of needing to get the One Thing right (which paradoxically might raise motivation for it), and I can make progress on multiple things at once. Again, I seem to excel and feel most motivated and rewarded when I&#39;m making incremental progress on a couple hobbies/projects at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host mentioned in the morning he likes to read some random(?) blog posts - the value of being exposed to new ideas/concepts/things that may not be what you normally consume / learn about. I like &lt;a href=&quot;http://kagi.com/smallweb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;Kagi Small Web&lt;/a&gt; for this purpose. I recently added it to my RSS feed viewer app (I use Feedly on Android) - specifically, the RSS feed for &amp;quot;appreciated&amp;quot; posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/podcasts/daniel-vassallo-indie-hackers-podcast/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                1 Second Everyday - Indie Hackers Podcast
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-09T23:09:37.775Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/podcasts/1-second-everyday-indie-hackers-podcast/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#podcast&quot;&gt;#podcast&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#entrepreneurship&quot;&gt;#entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#digitalgarden&quot;&gt;#digitalgarden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written on: 2025-12-07&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well hello there. This is my first ever attempt at an actual blog post / garden entry. Yesterday was the first day I learned of the concept of a Digital Garden, from a short bit of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6fj-OJ6RcNQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; (Relevant part at about 26:45 but the whole video is worth watching), which directed me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://maggieappleton.com/garden-history&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; for more context on Digital Gardens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, today, I was exploring more examples of the concept and read a couple relevant articles, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20250327004843/https://www.swyx.io/puwtpd&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Pick Up What They Put Down&lt;/a&gt;, which itself linked to the podcast that I&#39;m about to discuss. &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-s-this-podcast&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;What&#39;s this podcast?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiehackers.com/podcast/141-cesar-kuriyama-of-1-second-everyday&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Bootstrapping an App to Millions Through Sheer Persistence with Cesar Kuriyama of 1 Second Everyday&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;, published January 1, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a pretty good listen. It&#39;s about the founder of the app &amp;quot;1 Second Everyday&amp;quot;, which has you take a 1 second video of your life, or whatever you want, every day, and then, presumably whenever you&#39;d like to, export it into a continuous video of all those clips combined. I&#39;ve never used it before, but I&#39;ve definitely seen some other people&#39;s videos that they&#39;ve shared. They&#39;re fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!question]- Tangent on my use of PhotoChron (similar app)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have done something similar in the past with an outdated, possibly-no-longer-supported Android app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.photochron&amp;amp;hl=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;PhotoChron&lt;/a&gt;, which prompted me to take a picture just of my face everyday, so I could generate a cool timelapse of what I looked like (and what I was wearing, and what my background was) over time. I started in 2017 and mostly had been consistent (it&#39;s 2025 at the time I&#39;m writing this) with taking daily pictures, with some lapses here and there.&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m in a larger awkward period right now where I haven&#39;t done this in (I&#39;m ashamed to admit this to myself because I&#39;m kind of annoyed at losing the continuity) several months (or more) because I haven&#39;t redownloaded the app since getting a new phone (part of the problem is that it&#39;s no longer supported on the latest version of Android, so there&#39;d have to be some &amp;quot;hacking&amp;quot; around to get it to work -- honestly, I should just have been taking pictures in my normal photos app and putting them in an album or something, but then I lose the little oval in the middle of the screen that PhotoChron overlays over the viewfinder to show me where to put my face, and I lose the niceness of it saving the photos All Together in The Right Place and backing it up to the folder in Google Drive where I already have all the rest of the pictures.) -- All that being said, I&#39;ll get around to fixing this setup someday, because I think I do still value the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What drew me to listen to the podcast was that the PUWTPD article mentioned that the app had been featured in the movie Chef &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, which came about because the app&#39;s creator tweeted to Jon Favreau about something unrelated to the app, and then Jon Favreau found and liked the app via his profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual key word, though, that made me want to listen was &amp;quot;bootstrapping&amp;quot;. I love this term. It kind of makes me feel warm inside, in a nice way. I&#39;m not joking. And I am talking about it in its intended context in this podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bootstrapping is when you develop an app/website/service/project, probably with the goal of making some income from it, without going the &amp;quot;traditional&amp;quot; route of raising money via investors of venture capitalists or similar. Instead, you kind of just go and make the thing and find ways to monetize it and organically grow it. I&#39;m not exactly an expert on this topic, but it&#39;s the kind of thing that I want to do in the future to make something out of a personal project. I&#39;d definitely like to listen to more episodes of the Indie Hackers podcast in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally came across the term bootstrapping from a random video I stumbled upon (or maybe not so random) &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn3&quot; id=&quot;fnref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of this guy giving a talk... It stuck with me, though I haven&#39;t exactly followed it -- not yet at least. I intend to. &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn4&quot; id=&quot;fnref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway, this was an interesting listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;highlights&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some nice tidbits that stuck out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good callout to not be too secretive about your app idea. Probably no one is going to steal it, and even if they do, they probably won&#39;t have the same passion as you do. And there can be a lot of benefit in sharing your idea with others and having conversations about it and seeing what people might be interested in, etc.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really needed to hear this, because I have been working on an app idea (&lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/projects/software/specific-main-app-pursuit-i-m-currently-working-on/&quot;&gt;Specific Main App Pursuit I&#39;m Currently Working On&lt;/a&gt;) for at least a year (progress and effort have been too slow for my liking) and pretty much across the board I&#39;ve been not telling people about what I&#39;m working on -- though, that&#39;s more because I was scared that one slightly negative comment (or someone pointing out my idea already exists) would cause me to lose motivation to continue working on it, and less about someone stealing my idea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recently, though, I&#39;ve started talking about the idea to some people (because honestly it was just taking too long for me to create an MVP that I had to backtrack on the secret-keeping, perhaps in part to see if it would motivate me to work on it more frequently (it kind of has worked)). But hearing this reinforced from the podcast will certainly encourage me to do this more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was an interesting comment around the 44 minute mark when they were talking about the tweet to Jon Favreau. The app founder said that there&#39;s probably some tweet that anyone could make right now which could change their whole life. You would just need to identify what that tweet would be.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This kind of thought gives me chills. I find I want to believe it&#39;s true. It might take a billion alternate universe scenarios to find what that one tweet would be, but there probably is one out there. (Caveat that it&#39;d be easier to find a tweet that could destroy your life rather than generate tremendous positive change -- the former case makes me shudder, rather than positive chills, with a sort of call-of-the-void&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn5&quot; id=&quot;fnref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; type feeling.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This gives me similar vibes to thinking about the butterfly effect. You can track one small action in the past to where you are now. The tweet thing is kind of like a future projection of this. Maybe the tweet sets off a chain of events (like attracting the attention of a movie director on your app).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was a mention of the book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8978488-the-art-of-non-conformity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;The Art of Non-Conformity&lt;/a&gt; (don&#39;t remember the exact context in the podcast around it - something related to running your own business rather than working within a corporation I think). I checked and it was already on my to-read list. Seems like something I would like reading and would get something out of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Towards the end of the podcast, there was a discussion about future forms of social media, and what a &amp;quot;better&amp;quot; version of it would be. A platform that doesn&#39;t want you to just scroll infinitely so that you see more ads, or get more data collected about you. (This was in the context of the 1 Second Everyday app possibly having a form of feed / social media integrated in it in the future (and making it the &amp;quot;better&amp;quot; form). This podcast is a few years old, so maybe this is already a thing in the app.)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always an interesting topic, but right now it made me think of the concept of Digital Gardening, since in a way, I&#39;ve approached it from an alleyway of being frustrated with traditional social media not giving me the kind of platform that I&#39;ve felt myself craving for a while where I can have more meaningful engagement, both letting me put content/thoughts/writing out there (god forbid me putting this post in an Instagram caption or story) and receiving feedback/commentary in response to what I&#39;ve put out there (yes, I&#39;d like to participate in the other side of PUWTPD, too), and also just having a place where I can put my stuff and feeling more secure in it lasting there forever, and not having to worry about limitations like video length or worrying about &amp;quot;which account&amp;quot; to post something on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More directly related to what they were talking about on the podcast, though, is that the Digital Gardening concept is related to evading the &amp;quot;algorithm&amp;quot; and infinite-scrolling feeds. Blogging and longer form content in itself is an antidote to this. Engaging more deeply with specific content rather than flitting from one short video/image to the next. (The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6fj-OJ6RcNQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;  I mentioned earlier talks about this and other related antidotes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another video mentioned in the podcast that I&#39;d like to watch: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MNuOmTQdFjA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Stefan Sagmeister: The power of time off&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; (TED talk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s what was top on mind. I noted a couple things while listening to the podcast (I was on a walk in The Park) and I covered them all above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!danger]- Epilogue&lt;br /&gt;
One final note, on my experience writing this right now (spent about 1hr 45 min btw)... I&#39;ve had the idea of starting a more traditional blog here and there, but it always felt like a big scary task, so of course I never got to it. The concept of the Digital Garden helped me get the initiative to do it — mainly because of the emphasis that it&#39;s a living, growing thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&#39;t have to view an article as a one-and-done entity. I could have just written the first third of this page and been happy with it for now and still had it be public on the web and maybe send it to some people. I also don&#39;t have to worry about this being perfect and polished and super cohesive and meaningful... It&#39;s more of a scrapbook journaling vibe than a perfected portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also feel like I don&#39;t need to be self-conscious about what material is on here — meaning, my &amp;quot;first post&amp;quot; can be this arbitrary podcast episode that I listened to. There are seeds I need to plant in the garden that maybe normally would come first, like giving a brief summary of who I am, or expanding more on my ideas and purposes for this site. But I can plant those seeds another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another core concept of the Digital Garden is it not meant to be a chronological list of posts like a traditional blog — a post I write a year ago can be just as valuable and as open to being edited as any more recent post. Just the idea of having a hierarchy of categories and tags as a way to navigate a site, rather than a time-sorted list of posts, drew me in as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe these things aren&#39;t so different from traditional blogs, but the concept just gave me the push I needed (and surely some circumstances of general life right now, or the type of energy I&#39;ve had in the last few days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot; /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ideally I shall make a separate post about my feelings and inspiration for the Digital Garden concept, but I wanted to mention a bit here since this is the first post and it kind of led me directly to this podcast. Also, I can mention that I am kind of following the advice from &amp;quot;Pick Up What They Put Down&amp;quot; in that I&#39;m responding to a podcast that I just listened to (and kind of also responding to that article in a way). &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;(a movie I&#39;ve watched probably twice but only once really in my recent memory i.e. in the last five years -- great movie, and I&#39;m feeling inspired to watch it again because of the discussion on this podcast) &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;(TODO: Find this video and link it) &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn4&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given what goes on in my mind and with projects that I pursue, I would be surprised if I&#39;m not making a decisive effort (and hopefully succeeding) to generate passive income from a bootstrapped app/website in the next x years (no i&#39;m not defining x for you)  &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref4&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn5&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The call of the void describes the sudden, unexplained desire to participate in dangerous or self-destructive behaviors&amp;quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://health.clevelandclinic.org/call-of-the-void&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt; ) It&#39;s scary sometimes how easy it might be to ruin your own life. &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref5&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/podcasts/1-second-everyday-indie-hackers-podcast/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                The Chef of South Polar (2009)
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-15T23:29:51.163Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/movies/the-chef-of-south-polar-2009/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#movie&quot;&gt;#movie&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#japanese&quot;&gt;#japanese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Media%20I%20Have%20Consumed/Movies/Assets/chef%20of%20south%20polar.png&quot; alt=&quot;chef of south polar.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
IMDB: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1345728/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1345728/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Warning: Not much spoilers here I think but I don&#39;t guarantee that there are no spoilers.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I&#39;m being facetious, I&#39;d say that after my thoughts about the movie Chef (with Jon Favreau) that I mentioned in &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; target=&quot;&quot; data-note-icon=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/podcasts/1-second-everyday-indie-hackers-podcast/&quot;&gt;1 Second Everyday - Indie Hackers Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, which I mentioned inspired me to want to watch Chef again, I accidentally watched this movie instead. Well, that&#39;s basically what happened, but it wasn&#39;t accidental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was searching up Chef and took a glance a bit too far down the line, and saw Chef of South Polar with its 7/10 IMDB rating, which maybe doesn&#39;t sound like so notably high of a rating, but given that I stumbled upon it in happenstance and mingling with other incredibly random movies that had the word &amp;quot;Chef&amp;quot; in them, it impressed me enough to at least give the synopsis a read. My attention was snared. A movie about researchers in Antarctica with a focus on the chef that is with them. All this to say, I watched about 30 seconds of Jon Favreau&#39;s Chef, decided I didn&#39;t need to watch it again, watched just the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rkpwfnApDCo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;1 Second Everyday&amp;quot; clip&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube, and then settled in for The Chef of South Polar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And? It was a good movie. Great movie. I gave it 5/5 on Letterboxd. It was funny and relaxing and had beautiful cinematography, especially of the food&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Just an overall very chill and feel-good movie. It often made me think of Kim Stanley Robinson&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mars_trilogy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;Mars triology&lt;/a&gt; - the characters in that had to go through training in Antarctica to ensure they were psychologically fit to survive on Mars (due to the similar isolation and desertedness that Antarctica and Mars would share). Certainly the characters in the movie had a range of &amp;quot;well-adjustedness&amp;quot; to their conditions (meaning, sometimes not so well-adjusted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also emotion to the movie. There were a couple moments where I felt a wave of emotion (chills), albeit brief. Specifically, the food scene after the protag loses his daughter&#39;s tooth and then the others make a meal for him and he cries. The new-ramen scene was also quite cool and a tad bit of emotion too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of hilarious moments - these kind of stand out more as the essence of the movie (but are balanced by the brief but touching emotional parts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not a particularly fast-paced movie and there&#39;s not much plot, so it&#39;s mostly about enjoying the vibes and seeing how food brings these people together and laughing along with the silly situations they find themselves in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah and also, it being in Japanese, I appreciated it as a little motivator/challenge for my Japanese learning endeavors. It was nice to see myself catch some phrases and vocab words. I was particularly pleased when I was able to read &amp;quot;tanjoubi&amp;quot; (it was in hiragana in the movie. sorry, I don&#39;t have Japanese keyboard stuff setup on my laptop right now. I usually do that stuff on mobile.) on the cookies the chef was making and realize it was a birthday party seconds before they expanded on that visually. I&#39;m mostly in a slump regarding Japanese learning recently (I completed 11/12 Genki Volume 1 sections and haven&#39;t gone back to it in months) and I&#39;m not saying this movie is at all getting me out of it but it&#39;s a good reminder of the fun of language learning and the perks of learning more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot; /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m vegan. Given that most of the food pictured was not vegan, this summons thoughts and questions I ask myself about how I &amp;quot;should&amp;quot;  and &amp;quot;do&amp;quot; feel about appreciating the cinematography of non-vegan food. Frankly, it&#39;s a complicated stream of thoughts that I haven&#39;t fully developed in this moment, so I&#39;ll leave that as a discussion for another time. &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/movies/the-chef-of-south-polar-2009/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Bugonia (2025)
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-13T23:59:03.028Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/movies/bugonia-2025/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt12300742/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt12300742/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Media%20I%20Have%20Consumed/Movies/Assets/bugonia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bugonia.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!WARNING ] WARNING - SPOILERS AHEAD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have mixed feelings about this movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First: acting was great. Everything I&#39;m about to say is very much supported by the acting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was my experience with this movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard about the movie a couple months ago, and vaguely knew it was about someone maybe being an alien. I re-read the synopsis before watching it, which gave me more of a feeling that the character probably wasn&#39;t an alien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While watching it, I went back and forth several times whether I believed she was an alien or not. For most of the movie, the most plausible scenario was that she was not an alien. However, I knew there was a chance that there would be a twist and she would actually be an alien. (How many times can I say the word alien?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s kind of my problem with this. It feels like I was involved in a game between the director/writers and myself, where I was trying to puzzle this out, and the writers were tricking me until the very end. They won, honestly, and I was somewhat stricken at the end, or maybe actually self-satisfied due to my doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But again, it felt more like an interaction between my and the writers, with the actors as the vessels of that interaction. This... actually sounds very deep and probably is actually a reflection of the purpose of all art and such. However, I think I&#39;m actually trying to comment here about my level of investment in the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My understanding of the characters obviously changed after the big &amp;quot;reveal&amp;quot;. Suddenly, the crazy conspiracy theorist had actually been right about things. And the person we were empathizing with for most of the movie actually turned out to... go ahead and destroy all of humanity. (I do wish that last part was expanded on more. Why did the aliens need to kill everyone? I also have a problem with this because she displayed some empathy toward sidekick cousin guy right after his death (I think...), so how could she not care at all about wiping out civilization? Perhaps she lost all faith in humanity due to the events of this movie.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt that this would&#39;ve been a fine movie if the &amp;quot;twist&amp;quot; hadn&#39;t occurred. If it had just been about a CEO who was kidnapped and then managed to escape via her own wit. It would&#39;ve been a great movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ending cheapened it a little to me. It went from action/heist/drama to sci-fi. It cheapened my earlier understanding. But I&#39;m not necessarily saying this turned it into a &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; film. Just different. More wacky than the whole rest of the movie seemed. I read some review of the movie that said it should have been weirder earlier on, and maybe that would&#39;ve made this change less harsh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that being said -- I am generally here for the experience and ride that the makers have charted for me. And it was a fun experience. And I know this is a remake of a film, so I feel like I can&#39;t be upset about the plot being the plot. I guess I can just be criticizing both versions, but I don&#39;t feel I can do that without having also seen the original. And unfortunately I don&#39;t think I liked the experience enough to watch the original. Even if I like the idea of having a deeper experience with the material. Gotta choose what to put my time into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall. Good film. Fun. Thrilling at times. The twist ending was fun, but the execution of it with respect to the rest of the movie didn&#39;t sit totally right with me. But maybe that was the point.&lt;/p&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/media-i-have-consumed/movies/bugonia-2025/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Attending an Industry Reading
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-19T21:41:02.588Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/interests/theater/attending-an-industry-reading/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;I found myself at a stage reading for a musical called &amp;quot;Glory Ride&amp;quot;. It was called an &amp;quot;industry reading&amp;quot; (though I am not &amp;quot;Industry&amp;quot;). This was my first time attending a reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved the experience. And I am eager to attend more readings in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-the-experience&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;About the experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was part of an audience of about thirty people. A handful of those were people involved in the production itself -- director, stage managers, and similar. The rest were people in the &amp;quot;industry&amp;quot; (whatever that means) and others like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat in the front row (of three rows of chairs) so I was about 5 feet from where the rows of actors&#39; chairs started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work is under development. One scene of the second act was not included in the reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performance consisted of the actors reading dialogue and singing songs, with only piano accompaniment. There were some scenic cues read by (stage managers?) to make up for lack of a set to establish scenery or introduce what would have been acted out in the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-draws-me-to-this&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;What draws me to this&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being close to the magic, being behind the scenes, in a way. Nothing beats the ultra high resolution experience of sitting five feet away from such talented individuals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeing something when it&#39;s still a little rough around the edges and subject to change over time. Enhances my experience, adds depth to it, makes me feel like I&#39;m seeing part of the journey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gives me a feel for seeing how things work in the theater industry, what the progression from idea to polished show looks like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opportunity to meet interesting people, have conversations, learn new things. Maybe a chance to chat with actors or members of the production. Possibly even a chance to network in a way to help my far future self with his goal of maybe possible eventually getting involved with a community theater in a tech/crew role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-i-have-more-of-this&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;How can I have more of this?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep going to small shows and chat with people who go to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign up for mailing lists by production companies or theater spaces?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage existing connections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article about staged readings: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tdf.org/on-stage/tdf-stages/the-joys-of-staged-readings/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://www.tdf.org/on-stage/tdf-stages/the-joys-of-staged-readings/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/interests/theater/attending-an-industry-reading/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                2025 Music Retrospective
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-22T17:44:21.353Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/interests/music/2025-music-retrospective/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;The below &amp;quot;new approach&amp;quot; isn&#39;t all there is to be said about my music consumption this year, but it&#39;s a major part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-approach-to-music-discovery&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;A new approach to music discovery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this year, my approach to music discovery looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen to songs I already like, and let Spotify auto-play (usually related/similar) songs after I finish listening to specific songs or albums&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take album recommendations from friends or the internet and listen through those albums&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Occasionally find a song, artist, or album that I really liked, and then maybe obsessively listen to their stuff until I&#39;m fully saturated on their content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide it&#39;s time to branch back out and begin exploring again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But something I noticed is that I would really like certain songs or albums only after listening to them multiple times, and sometimes those &amp;quot;multiple times&amp;quot; could be spread out over a long period of time. I usually add a song to my &amp;quot;Liked songs&amp;quot; in Spotify, but that doesn&#39;t mean I&#39;ll listen to it again anytime soon. If it took two listens for me to really like something, and there is a very long gap between my first listen and second listen, it feels like there is some level of &amp;quot;wasted&amp;quot; time or opportunity with regards to how quickly I can gain appreciation for a song I&#39;ve heard once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also incurs a concern that I might listen to a song once, and never listen to it again, but if I had listened to it again, there could be high reward in terms of appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for a big chunk of this year, I tried an approach that was aimed at getting me to more frequently listen back to albums that caught my interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of a &amp;quot;cycle&amp;quot;, I would use one of the music discovery methods (from auto-play, or recommendations) and then if an album caught my interest enough that it felt like it was worth listening to more, I created a new playlist and added the full album to the playlist. I then gave the playlist a name, pretty always a random phrase that popped into my head at that exact moment. I then AI-generated an image, based on the name I came up with and my current sentiment in that moment, and used it as the playlist cover image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then for any other albums I liked within this time span, I added those to that current playlist as well, until the playlist hit around 3-5 albums total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was then that in moments when I didn&#39;t have anything specific I wanted to listen to, I would turn to this playlist as my default just-play-something playlist. This way, I would continue to expose myself to these albums repeatedly, and perhaps develop an appreciation for them, to a degree that I wouldn&#39;t have if I had just let the albums float by and maybe chance upon them later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually after a month or two, I would feel like I had consumed the albums from that playlist enough, and I would start a new cycle for the next new album that interested me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another note on why I did this at the album level rather than for individual songs: Part of my general music discovery process is that if I like one or a couple songs on an album, I usually end up liking a lot more of the other songs on the album, as I listen to it over time. This is part of the core theory of why I started this playlist approach, to create a structure of exposing myself to all the songs in an album over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-this-go&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;How did this go?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started strong and then fizzled towards the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really liked the cadence at the beginning. It felt like I was developing more of an appreciation for the albums I was adding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a flaw from the start, though, or maybe not a flaw but just something for me to be aware of. I might add an album to one of the playlists and not end up liking the album beyond my early listen. But I think that&#39;s okay. The point of this is to see what I end up liking more after repeat listens. The ones I care about will stand out. But it does mean that there are just some &amp;quot;dead&amp;quot; albums in these playlists. Ones that I don&#39;t care much about but which are still there. I think that&#39;s okay. These playlists are meant to be &amp;quot;discovery&amp;quot; playlists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s another ambiguity. During this process, there are several albums that became &lt;strong&gt;major favorites&lt;/strong&gt;. However, I don&#39;t know if I can attribute that appreciation as being caused by this playlist approach, or if they inevitably would have become one of my &amp;quot;obsessions&amp;quot; after a first listen. I&#39;ll never know the answer to this, but what&#39;s important is that I found them and kept listening to them. That being said, I do think that the playlist approach had an impact here. at least to some extent. It kept the music on my radar, made it feel imminent, and brought me back to it as a sort of default, which perhaps I wouldn&#39;t have done as much otherwise. (Primarily I am thinking about albums from the band &amp;quot;Larry and His Flask&amp;quot; for this big win.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do truly feel that I developed deep appreciation for several albums due to this process. The real value here was in giving me a place to keep albums that I wanted to pay more attention to. So I don&#39;t lose them when I at first become interested. I don&#39;t have to scramble and search and remember which albums I wanted to focus on. They were right there in my current-cycle playlist. This aid on its own did a lot for helping me to have the focus I needed to pay proper attention to the albums I felt interest in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did it fizzle toward the end of the year? I think partly it&#39;s because I became a bit more Broadway-focus in the last few months. Probably it started once I was exposed to Into The Woods, and suddenly I switched into theater-mode and I didn&#39;t need to track these in the playlist style. For some reason, theater just feels like a different part of my music journey and so I instinctively did not want to integrate show albums into my music discovery playlist process. And I think that&#39;s fine. The real effect here is that I was way more interested in the theater music than doing proper music discovery like I was doing for the rest of the year before then. And then once I mostly got past that Broadway phase, I made one more &amp;quot;cycle&amp;quot; playlist, but it was way more fragmented and I wasn&#39;t feeling the drive to add albums to it and listen back to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;will-i-do-this-again-next-year&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Will I do this again next year?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe, maybe not. I&#39;m interested in exploring other ways to manage music interest. I still believe in the principle that structured repeat exposure can lead to developing an appreciating for music that otherwise I wouldn&#39;t get. I&#39;m not sure my above approach is the perfect one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, I&#39;ll go with the flow. I seem to be on a break from the playlist approach now (at the end of the year), and I have a feeling that break will continue for a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don&#39;t think my value of discovering new music is going away anytime soon, so I wouldn&#39;t be surprised if I seek out new ways to encourage and cultivate that, or continue this playlist approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-playlists&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The playlists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Interests/Music/Assets/Pasted%20image%2020251222113413.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pasted image 20251222113413.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Rabbit Enters Winter - Created Dec 21, 2024&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standout albums:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;SELF-iSH&amp;quot; by Will Wood and the Tapeworms
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of these songs became obsessions. I love them but they are kind of dark in a goofy, twisted way. Later in the year, I was generally hesitant to listen back to these because I guess I wasn&#39;t feeling like a return into darkness, but they are great songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Reality vs. the Optimist&amp;quot; by Kiss Kiss
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish I listened to this one more, I liked it but Will Wood kind of dominated my focus of this playlist. Want to go back to this more in the future. Does have a similar vibe to the Will Wood songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Riding a Black Unicorn...&amp;quot; by Aurelio Voltaire
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I surprised myself with appreciating these. If I recall correctly, I got drawn in by &amp;quot;When the Circus Came to Town&amp;quot; (given my circus/juggling interests), but many of the other songs kept me in. Some of them are also quite dark and graphic. And I just plainly do not like &amp;quot;The Dirtiest Song That Ain&#39;t&amp;quot;. But &amp;quot;Riding a black unicorn&amp;quot; (the song), &amp;quot;The Mechanical Girl&amp;quot;, and a couple of the others are high re-listenability to me. They are a bit silly and theatrical though. Not really my usual vibe, and it&#39;s not the most sophisticated feeling. I&#39;m interested in exploring more Aurelio Voltaire (he&#39;s known for spooky Halloween music) but I made an initial attempt at some point and didn&#39;t catch onto the one or two other albums I checked out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Rockin&#39; the Suburbs&amp;quot; by Ben Folds
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I discovered Ben Folds through a couple songs he did with Regina Spektor (who is one of my earliest music interests (started with the song Eet, and then when she did a SummerStage concert in NYC a couple years ago I got into a bunch of her other songs) and then decided to explore his other music, hence why this album got added here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ended up liking a bunch of the songs in this album. Looking at the songs, though, &amp;quot;Zak and Sara&amp;quot; is the only one that stands out in memory, and I can&#39;t remember what most of the others were like. I liked them, though, and would listen more (though I honestly haven&#39;t much).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Interests/Music/Assets/Pasted%20image%2020251222113520.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pasted image 20251222113520.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Somebody Called You (Thrumming) - Created Feb 27, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every album in this one was standout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;...And the Battle Begun&amp;quot; by Rx Bandits
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This likely has a spot in my favorite albums of all time. The musical sound is so unique to me, I don&#39;t know what else to compare it to. I can&#39;t name top tracks, partly because I love most (if not all) of them, and partly because I honestly always forget what song the titles go with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surprisingly, I also find that I probably don&#39;t know most of the lyrics that well. I&#39;m usually strongly lyric-minded. But even if the lyrics are not as memorable (or maybe just hard for me to follow because they are kind of fast paced), the sound of the music comes through extremely strong. There are totally still little snippets of the catchiest lyrics that I know, but these perhaps just aren&#39;t the type of songs that make me feel the &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; to memorize the lyrics (unlike Streetlight Manifest (my favorite band in the last few years), whose lyrics almost all become an instant need for being memorized)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Ten Stories&amp;quot; by mewithoutYou
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to listen to this more (and listen to their other albums). Another unique kind of sound for me, which I really liked. Often giving spoken-word vibes, leaning into aggressive-rage spoken word (not like heavy-metal rage vibes, but like, someone really passionately and strongly and intensely speaking their spoken words. I love it. &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associate this with an airport waiting for plane, I was listening to a bunch of the songs while waiting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;By the Lamplight&amp;quot; by Larry and His Flask
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The caveat here is that Larry and His Flask was already waaaay on my radar, and I would have listened to them plenty whether they were in this playlist or not, but I do think that adding it to this playlist reinforced it and made absolute sure I would keep going back to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry and His Flask was the artist of the year for me, absolutely. If 2024 was the year of Streetlight Manifesto (and it was), 2025 was the year of Larry and His Flask (but still, look at all my other favorites in this overall list, there were so many standouts this year that I feel a little weird pointing LAHF as the &lt;a class=&quot;tag&quot; onclick=&quot;toggleTagSearch(this)&quot; data-content=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;#1&lt;/a&gt;, but it still feels right to say.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I like so much? The strong vocals (the lead singer has a really nice voice), love the lyrics and general themes, and the musicality and folky vibes are all great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;The Script&amp;quot; by The Script
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This feels like an &amp;quot;education&amp;quot; pick to me. Like, I was culturing myself with a classic. I don&#39;t know if The Script is supposed to be considered a classic. But it feels that way to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ended up liking a lot of the songs, so definitely a win. They didn&#39;t stay on my radar after this playlist&#39;s cycle though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must also mention that the LAHF album has a song called &amp;quot;Muffled Thrums&amp;quot;, which is not at all the reason I called the playlist &amp;quot;Thrumming&amp;quot;, but I am enamored with that fact that it worked out like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created this playlist during a car ride (and an image of that ride flashes into my mind when I think about the origins of the playlist title).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During that car ride, I also used ChatGPT to get a couple of these recs -- specifically for Rx Bandits and mewithoutYou (for those specific albums I added) -- essentially seeding this playlist with those. Specifically I was asking ChatGPT for recs similar to Streetlight Manifesto. The pros and cons of AI for this can surely be debated, but clearly it paid off here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[!INFO]- My AI prompting&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Suggest me music artists and a suggested album from them that matches my interest. I usually like indie and rock, but am open to other things. I like streetlight manifesto because of the following descriptors. Strong lyrics that have meaning and make you think, that are sung with powerful and energetic vocals with a catchy beautiful melody and great instrumental along with it.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;List some more that are slightly beyond my familiar zone but still fit the descriptors&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Which of all the above recs would be highest energy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually I&#39;m going to preserve all of its recs, in case I want to access them from here in the future, so I&#39;m now prompting it to give a concise list of all album recs it gave:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Crane Wife, The Decemberists (2006) – Poetic, deeply thought-out lyrics inspired by folklore and literature, delivered with passionate vocals and dynamic, theatrical compositions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sunset Tree, The Mountain Goats (2005) – John Darnielle writes intensely personal, story-driven lyrics with raw energy and emotion, often dealing with survival and resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Monitor, Titus Andronicus (2010) – A chaotic yet anthemic rock opera drawing on historical themes with cathartic, passionate vocals and heavy instrumentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go Farther in Lightness, Gang of Youths (2017) – Philosophical, life-affirming lyrics with dramatic, soaring instrumentation and emotionally charged vocals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…And the Battle Begun, Rx Bandits (2006) – Complex musicianship, politically charged lyrics, and progressive rock influences built on ska-punk intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere at the Bottom of the River Between Vega and Altair, La Dispute (2008) – Emotionally devastating spoken-word-infused post-hardcore with poetic, introspective lyrics and dynamic instrumentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Greatest Generation, The Wonder Years (2013) – Introspective, storytelling-driven pop punk with deeply personal, self-reflective lyrics and huge, anthemic choruses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drunken Lullabies, Flogging Molly (2002) – Irish folk-punk with raucous energy, meaningful social commentary, and beautiful, haunting melodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brother, Sister, mewithoutYou (2006) – Emotionally raw, poetic lyrics with spoken-word/post-hardcore delivery and intricate instrumentation blending indie rock and folk influences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Painted Shut, Hop Along (2015) – Frances Quinlan&#39;s raspy, impassioned vocals paired with deeply narrative and literary songwriting, backed by dynamic indie rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transgender Dysphoria Blues, Against Me! (2014) – Raw, anthemic punk rock with intensely personal and politically charged lyrics, delivered with fiery, commanding vocals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift Your Skinny Fists Like Antennas to Heaven, Godspeed You! Black Emperor (2000) – No vocals, but this is post-rock at its most cinematic—deeply emotional, thought-provoking, and epic in scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Super Taranta!, Gogol Bordello (2007) – Gypsy punk with wild, energetic instrumentation, theatrical vocals, and rebellious, deeply political lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ants From Up There, Black Country, New Road (2022) – Avant-garde indie with orchestral elements, deeply emotional storytelling, and vocals that teeter between spoken and sung with intense vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shake Shook Shaken, The Dø (2014) – Experimental indie-pop with hypnotic vocals and electronic-leaning but deeply human, poetic songwriting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Alchemy Index (Vols I &amp;amp; II – Fire &amp;amp; Water), Thrice (2007) – A conceptual rock album with poetic, mythic lyrics, balancing heavy, intense rock (“Fire”) and atmospheric, haunting beauty (“Water”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Act III: Life and Death, The Dear Hunter (2009) – Progressive rock at its most cinematic, with lush orchestration and powerful melodies in a narrative-driven concept album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lighght, Kishi Bashi (2014) – Playful and intricate chamber pop, blending violin-driven melodies with deeply emotional lyrics and stunning vocal harmonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Interests/Music/Assets/Pasted%20image%2020251222122129.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pasted image 20251222122129.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bubbles Rising to the Surface - Created April 8th, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I like the title of the playlist more than the individual albums. HOWEVER, that&#39;s not to say I didn&#39;t like the music. Just not as memorable as other albums this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still worth mentioning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Absolution&amp;quot; by Muse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;PIPER CoolSelection&amp;quot; by PIPER&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Stick Season&amp;quot; by Noah Kahan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Fight With Tools&amp;quot; by Flobots
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flobots is one of my favorite artists. I don&#39;t know this album that well so I threw it in here. It honestly didn&#39;t serve that well here, I don&#39;t recall listening to it much in this playlist. Slowly appreciating this album over time, though. (My top Flobots album is &amp;quot;Circle in the Square&amp;quot;. My entrypoint into Flobots was &amp;quot;Me &amp;amp; You (Happy 2gether)&amp;quot;, which is their cover of the song by The Turtles. Love their cover of it so much - they rap/hip-hop-ified it.) I haven&#39;t found a hip hop group that I like as much as Flobots yet (I am very inexperienced in Hip Hop, so take that statement with a grain of salt.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Interests/Music/Assets/Pasted%20image%2020251222122729.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pasted image 20251222122729.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Enthused Disruption - Created May 14, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m starting to realize that this whole &amp;quot;playlist approach&amp;quot; peaked with the first two playlists. Am I making a bigger deal about this than the impact it actually had??? Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one had &amp;quot;Mr. A-Z&amp;quot; by Jason Mraz, &amp;quot;MAD!&amp;quot; by Sparks (their latest album), &amp;quot;Everything Besides&amp;quot; by Larry and His Flask (adding it here definitely made me listen to it and appreciate it), and &amp;quot;This is How We Get Better&amp;quot; by The Narcissist Cookbook (very interesting album, liked it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Interests/Music/Assets/Pasted%20image%2020251222123123.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pasted image 20251222123123.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finding My Way Home - Created July 20, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll say this one had high impact as well. If only because it got me listening to Midlake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;The Trials of Van Occupanther&amp;quot; by Midlake
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love a lot of these songs. Especially &amp;quot;Van Occupanther&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Roscoe&amp;quot;, with honorable mention to &amp;quot;Head Home&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;It Covers the Hillsides&amp;quot;. This album took measurable real estate in my mind. It belongs in the list of top albums for the year (if I were to make one). The songs are on the chiller side. Don&#39;t remember exactly how I found them. But I love them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Six Demon Bag&amp;quot; by Man Man
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liked some of the songs, but honestly never got that into it. Would listen to more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;All Eternals Deck&amp;quot; by The Mountain Goats
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think it&#39;s inevitable that I listen to more Mountain Goats in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liked a bunch of songs in this album. Not particularly standout, but I liked the vibe. Mostly chill too, slower songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standouts are &amp;quot;Damn These Vampires&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Age of Kings&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/img/user/Interests/Music/Assets/Pasted%20image%2020251222123534.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pasted image 20251222123534.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fastly, Slowly, Breathe - Created October 2, 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is the &amp;quot;fizzle&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started with me adding &amp;quot;Red, Yellow &amp;amp; Blue&amp;quot; by Born Ruffians. I liked some of the songs but still haven&#39;t listened to them much. Then in mid-November I added &amp;quot;The Ides&amp;quot; by Me Like Bees. I think I&#39;m going to listen to Me Like Bees more moving forward, but I didn&#39;t really listen to them through this playlist, but instead in Spotify&#39;s shuffles after other songs I queued up, or through song radios for related music. Again, the &amp;quot;fizzle&amp;quot; is that I&#39;m not really going to the playlist as my &amp;quot;default&amp;quot; currently, like I did earlier in the year. And then I added &amp;quot;The First Edition&amp;quot; by Kenny Rogers a couple days ago, but I&#39;m not sure how much impact it&#39;ll have -- the song of interest was &amp;quot;Just Dropped In (To See What Condition My Condition Was In)&amp;quot;, which is a funny song that showed up from my previously-hearted songs (I was playing my liked songs on shuffle).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;end-o-the-year&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;End &#39;o the year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bomb the Music Industry - this is the strongest artist in my mind for the last month or so. Otherwise, there&#39;s been a cycle of some theater stuff, and a little bit of Larry and His Flask and Streetlight Manifesto sprinkled in here and there. I kind of haven&#39;t been listening to that much music recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-theater-music-i-got-into-this-year&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;The theater music I got into this year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Outsiders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Octet (Dave Malloy, mostly the first track The Forest)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Into The Woods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natasha, Pierre, and the Great Comet of 1812&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghost Quartet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bat Boy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned earlier that getting into some of these led to my playlist approach fizzling towards the end of the year. I&#39;d say that&#39;s mostly attributed to Into The Woods, Great Comet, and Ghost Quartet. Outsiders was earlier in the year (April) and Octet and Bat Boy were minor influences on that. (Note, Outsiders in the above list is the only show I actually went to this year. I went to other Broadway musicals as well, but their albums did not dominate much listening time.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great year for discovering new music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s definitely an &lt;em&gt;Ebb and Flow&lt;/em&gt; to the cycles of consuming what I already like, exploring new music, and just not listening to that much stuff at all. Gotta respect that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as I said earlier, there are ups and downs (meaning, ambiguous benefits) of this time-based playlist approach. But I&#39;m glad I tried it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot; /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;yes I know this is technically not 2025, but it basically is, and it&#39;s the first of this playlist approach, so I&#39;m not going to exclude it &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saying this makes me also think of my more recent listening interests, Bomb the Music Industry (becoming a big favorite!) and Apes of State (less favorite but similar intense-word vibes I&#39;m talking about here and also similar to BTMI), which btw neither of which are part of these playlists) &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/interests/music/2025-music-retrospective/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                On Cooking - Veganism and Whole-Food Plant-Based Diet
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-17T20:09:47.422Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/interests/food/on-cooking-veganism-and-whole-food-plant-based-diet/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;I&#39;m vegan. I approached this from a health-perspective first (WFPB), which led to a gradual transition to eating more plant based foods. Then I learned about the ethical philosophies behind resisting animal exploitation and went fully strict on following veganism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I cook for myself, I prefer to follow the principles of a whole-food plant-based (WFPB) diet as much as possible. When I eat at a restaurant, I just follow veganism but not WFPB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-wfpb&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;What is WFPB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t follow WFPB 100% strictly all the time. But, these are the core principles of the WFPB diet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*Minimize animal products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimize processed foods &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimize refined sugars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimize refined grains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimize oils &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Technically, someone can follow a WFPB diet but not be fully vegan. The WFPB diet&#39;s principles say you should minimize animal products due to their health concerns. However, since I also am a strict vegan, I adhere to completely cutting out animal products. &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn3&quot; id=&quot;fnref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; you eat on a WFPB diet? The standard list is: fruits, vegetables, whole grains, beans, nuts, and seeds. More broadly, it&#39;s any foods derived from plants which are minimally processed. The list may sound small, but there&#39;s a lot of variation in ingredients and there is a huge variety of dishes to be enjoyed. Many, if not most (if not all) cultures around the world have dishes which are already vegan (if not WFPB) or easily modifiable to be so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting back to my own cooking philosophy -- as mentioned, when I cook for myself, I prefer to adhere to WFPB as much as possible, but I do make small exceptions on rare occasions. When I eat at a restaurant, I don&#39;t think much about WFPB&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn4&quot; id=&quot;fnref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and I primarily focus on finding vegan options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;experimentation-cooking-for-others&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Experimentation + Cooking for others&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s another big exception to WFPB that I make: when I want to follow a vegan but non-WFPB recipe to create something more tasty (or just tasty in a different way) than a WFPB counterpart would be, either to experiment for my own understanding of the possibilities of food and cuisine, or to create positive experiences with vegan food for friends or family or others who may be tasting the food I prepare. If I am to have a &amp;quot;mission&amp;quot; related to cooking, it would be to help others to see that vegan foods can be delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WFPB is very much about health and longevity for me. Veganism on its own is about doing what&#39;s right for the sake of fellow animals that can&#39;t speak for themselves - drawing attention to and making efforts to stop their unnecessary suffering and exploitation (when plant-based alternatives can provide 100% sufficient nutrition for humans)&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn5&quot; id=&quot;fnref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In other words: WFPB is for myself &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn6&quot; id=&quot;fnref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, whereas veganism is to help other sentient&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn7&quot; id=&quot;fnref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; beings who are in need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I&#39;m trying to say with the above: I&#39;m willing to violate my WFPB principles when I&#39;m aiming to cook delicious things for other people. I want people&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn8&quot; id=&quot;fnref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to have as positive a perception as possible of vegan foods. Making things &amp;quot;healthier&amp;quot;, though I can deeply appreciate the tastes for myself (and do hope others can too), sometimes or often does not lend to the tastiest, at least in a mainstream way&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn9&quot; id=&quot;fnref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I want people to have as positive as possible a perception&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn10&quot; id=&quot;fnref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of vegan food? It&#39;s not like I think I&#39;m going to directly convert people toward veganism like this. But even planting a seed in someone&#39;s head that maybe possible there could be a chance that they could survive with maybe even just this little percentage of a type of food that they eat, without an animal being involved, could be okay and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;talking-about-veganism-and-amp-challenging-yourself&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Talking about veganism &amp;amp; Challenging yourself&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether this is true or not, I imagine some discomfort, if not stronger emotion, when someone reads this and notices that I wish for more people to become vegan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I&#39;m not going to deny that it&#39;s true that I want more people to become vegan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s my stance. What&#39;s yours?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we have an honest conversation about our food systems and ways of eating and move towards a mutual understanding about each of our perspectives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I challenge you? Are you open to being challenged?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your mind open to some ideas that might be different than what you&#39;re used to? Maybe different than what you&#39;ve believed for your entire life? Can you evaluate these things with honest integrity and be open to change if what you hear is logical and reasonable? Maybe you&#39;re not ready for change right now, and that&#39;s okay. But if you really stop and genuinely think about the arguments for veganism, can you honestly and truly say that you &lt;em&gt;shouldn&#39;t&lt;/em&gt; change something?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not saying the answer should be 100% for sure one way or the other for you. But I do request, when you have the capacity to, to learn about the reasons for veganism, to question the norm, to fully and deeply engage with the issue and the discussion, and to have an open mind to the possibility of adjusting your course, if it makes sense to you to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a fully-fleshed argument for veganism. Mainly I wanted to discuss my mindset around cooking. It&#39;s inevitably tied to the vegan discussion though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources-about-veganism-and-wfpb&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Resources about veganism and WFPB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we&#39;re here, then, some resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z3u7hXpOm58&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z3u7hXpOm58&lt;/a&gt; (&amp;quot;You Will Never Look at Your Life in the Same Way Again&amp;quot; by Earthling Ed) This is the video that convinced me to follow the ethical side of veganism (it&#39;s just a guy giving a talk, no gory imagery or anything like that). This guy&#39;s channel has a lot of interesting tabled debates about veganism that also likely swayed me and are entertaining to watch. (Can you challenge yourself to watch these and engage with what&#39;s being discussed?))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the reddit post that made me start thinking about health for longevity purposes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/longevity/comments/ci5vu1/i_am_a_22_yo_healthy_male_who_wants_to_live_until/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/longevity/comments/ci5vu1/i_am_a_22_yo_healthy_male_who_wants_to_live_until/&lt;/a&gt; - There&#39;s one comment in there that references the whole food plant based diet, and I&#39;m guessing that&#39;s what seeded my exposure to WFPB. Also likely seeded my avoidance of alcohol (or at least the health aspect of avoiding alcohol&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fn11&quot; id=&quot;fnref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some other resources about WFPB diet
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nutritionstudies.org/whole-food-plant-based-diet-guide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://nutritionstudies.org/whole-food-plant-based-diet-guide/&lt;/a&gt; - Another guide on WFPB. This site also is a great resource for WFPB recipes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summary of &amp;quot;How Not To Die&amp;quot;, a book that talks about the benefits of the WFPB diet in preventing and reversing many of the most common dietary-related causes of death in humans. It also includes a detailed list of &amp;quot;green&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;yellow&amp;quot;/&amp;quot;red foods (green is healthy, yellow is foods to steer away from but okay in limited quantities, red is foods to generally always avoid) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chewfo.com/diets/how-not-to-die-by-michael-greger-md-food-list-what-to-eat-and-foods-to-avoid/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://www.chewfo.com/diets/how-not-to-die-by-michael-greger-md-food-list-what-to-eat-and-foods-to-avoid/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plantbasedcookingshow.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;https://plantbasedcookingshow.com/&lt;/a&gt; A cooking blog/youtube channel that strictly follows WFPB for recipes. So many great recipes that use dried dates as a refined sugar replacement in dessert recipes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot; /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;processed&amp;quot; can mean a lot of things. Cutting a vegetable is processing it. In the context of the WFPB diet, &amp;quot;processed&amp;quot; is usually taken to mean &amp;quot;heavily&amp;quot; processed or having many additives &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;this doesn&#39;t mean avoid all sources of fat. You get lots of good, healthy fats from peanut butter and avocados, for example. Refined oils are empty calories without nutritional value, and can cause buildup of health issues. I acknowledge that I am not backing these claims with direct sources right now, but a search for wfpb health benefits should bring up more info about this and the other points. &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would say it&#39;s a good thing for the principles to have this laxness about not needing to go 100% vegan right away. It makes it less intimidating. It gave me the opportunity to slowly transition away from animal products, without feeling intense pressure to immediately give up all animal products, a drastic change that may have scared me away. I slowly realized that I didn&#39;t need animal products in my life, before making the full switch. &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn4&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s just less realistic to expect restaurant dishes to be oil and sugar free, unless the restaurant specializes in that &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref4&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn5&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is basically my &amp;quot;why am I vegan&amp;quot; summed up in a sentence, but I eventually will expand and write more on this. &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref5&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn6&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;(my own selfish desire to increase the length and quality of my life by eating as healthy as possible to reduce the chance of dietary-related illnesses later in life) &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref6&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn7&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know what you&#39;re thinking. How can I claim that animals are sentient? This is too deep of a discussion for a footnote. But I&#39;ll just say: You wouldn&#39;t like if I kicked a dog. Why? Because it displays visual evidence of its suffering. Surely a pig or cow would display something similar. And yet we (non-vegans) are okay with (albeit indirectly) paying for someone to hurt and kill them? Something doesn&#39;t align here. (Ok that wasn&#39;t exactly about the term &#39;sentient&#39; but it&#39;s related. Perhaps instead of &amp;quot;sentient&amp;quot;, I mean &amp;quot;creatures who we understand to be able to feel pain, experience suffering, and have a desire to not die.) &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref7&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn8&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m tempted to say &amp;quot;the world&amp;quot; but realistically, my sphere of influence is the people that I interact with in my direct small community. Which is a great impact to make, in my opinion. Change starts small and local. &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref8&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn9&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;because seriously, even with 100% WFPB, things can be incredibly tasty and I wouldn&#39;t want them in any other form &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref9&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn10&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;(apapap) &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref10&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn11&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;yes there are several other aspects of this, to be expanded on elsewhere &lt;a href=&quot;https://briancherin.github.io/#fnref11&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/interests/food/on-cooking-veganism-and-whole-food-plant-based-diet/" />
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <title>
                Writing
                
            </title>
            <updated>2025-12-15T04:09:58.005Z</updated>
            <id>https://briancherin.github.io/interests/creative/writing/writing/</id>
            <content type="html">
                &lt;p&gt;The kinds of writing I pursue or intend to pursue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public-facing blog, i.e. Here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal, private journaling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creative storywriting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;

            </content>
            <link href="https://briancherin.github.io/interests/creative/writing/writing/" />
        </entry>
</feed>

